<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0b5/rng/docbook.rng" type="xml"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xml:lang="en" xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0">
    <info>
        <title>2.3.1 Release Notes</title>
        <edition>15 January 2007 - version 2.3.1</edition>
    </info>
    <sect1 xml:id="overview">
        <title>Overview</title>
        <para>2.3.1 offers a handful of critical fixes to the 2.3.0 release, for both performance and security. To see the feature enhancements of the 2.3 series, see the <link xl:href="../2.3.0/release-notes.html">2.3.0 release notes</link>.  For the bug fixes in 2.3.1, see below.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="migration">
        <title>Migrating from earlier versions</title>
        <para>A migration from 2.2 to 2.3 is a smaller step than from 2.1 to 2.2, but what
            conversions and alterations do need to be performed are identified below.</para>
        <sect2 xml:id="migration-db">
            <title>Database Conversion</title>
            <para>A DB conversion script is required for a database migration from 2.2.2 to 2.3.1.</para>
            <note>
                <title>Note</title>
                <para>DB conversions require the successive application of all intermediate scripts,
                    e.g., a migration from 2.1.2 will require three conversions: one from 2.1.2 to
                    2.2.0, one from 2.2.0 to 2.2.1, and then one from 2.2.2 to 2.3.1 (there was no
                    DB conversion between 2.2.1 and 2.2.2).</para>
            </note>

            <para>The conversion scripts to be applied - in distinct versions for MySQL and Oracle,
                respectively - are found in the <filename>reference/docs/conversion</filename>
                folder of the release or on subversion: <link
                    xl:href="https://source.sakaiproject.org/svn/reference/tags/sakai_2-3-1/docs/conversion"
                    >https://source.sakaiproject.org/svn/reference/tags/sakai_2-3-1/docs/conversion</link></para>
        </sect2>
        
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="resolved">
        <title>Fixes Included in this Release</title>
        <para>Sakai 2.3.1 fixes the following issues:</para>
        <para>
            <link xl:href="fixed-issues.html">
                http://source.sakaiproject.org/release/2.3.1/fixed-issues.html</link>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="open-issues">
        <title>Open Issues</title>
        <para>The list of known issues with Sakai 2.3.1 is found at:</para>
        <para>
            <link xl:href="open-issues.html">
                http://source.sakaiproject.org/release/2.3.1/open-issues.html</link>
        </para>
        <para>See in particular the "Important Issues" noted at the top of the list.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1 xml:id="maintenance">
        <title>Maintenance Branch</title>
        <para>The code of each release has a corresponding maintenance branch, which is patched with
            fixes in an ongoing way by a branch manager - effectively until there is no longer
            sufficient interest in it for a branch manager to volunteer. Maintenance branches
            therefore represent the latest snapshot of fixes for any given Sakai version.</para>
        <para>These maintenance branches may be checked out through subversion; they are labeled
            with an 'x' replacing their minor version number, e.g. '2-3-x'. You can check out the
            2.3 maintenance branch with the following command: </para>
        <para>
            <command>svn co
            https://source.sakaiproject.org/svn/sakai/branches/sakai_2-3-x/</command>
        </para>
        <para>If you come upon an important fix that you believe should be included in the branch
            (and perhaps isn't yet), feel free to bring it to the attention of the branch manager,
            Lance Speelmon (lance@indiana.edu).</para>
    </sect1>
</article>
